The most terrifying film you will ever experience.
Evil Dead is a horror film directed by Fede Álvarez.
Mia, a drug addict, is determined to kick the habit.
To that end, she asks her brother, David, his girlfriend, Natalie and their friends Olivia and Eric to
accompany her to their family's remote forest cabin to help her through withdrawal.
Eric finds a mysterious Book of the Dead at the cabin and
reads aloud from it, awakening an ancient demon.
All hell breaks loose when the malevolent entity possesses Mia.
Mia Allen, played by Jane Levy.
David Allen, played by Shiloh Fernandez.
Eric, played by Lou Taylor Pucci.
Olivia, played by Jessica Lucas.
Natalie, played by Elizabeth Blackmore.
Teenager, played by Phoenix Connolly.
Evil Dead is a 2013 American supernatural horror film directed by Fede
Álvarez, who co-wrote the screenplay with Rodo Sayagues.
It is the fourth installment in the Evil Dead film series and stars Jane Levy, Shiloh
Fernandez, Lou Taylor Pucci, Jessica Lucas, and Elizabeth Blackmore.
The story follows a group of five people under attack by
dead people in a remote cabin in the woods.
Talks for a fourth Evil Dead film began in 2004, with original film actor Bruce
Campbell about the possibility for a next film in the franchise.
The project was officially announced in July 2011, with Ghost House Pictures producing it, Diablo
Cody in the process of revising the script, and Fede Álvarez chosen as the director.
Much of the cast joined from January to February 2012.
Principal photography took place in March 2012 and wrapped in May in
New Zealand outside of Auckland, lasting about a month.
Evil Dead had its premiere at South by Southwest on March 8, 2013, and was released in the United
States on April 5, by Sony Pictures Releasing through the TriStar Pictures label.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and grossed $97
million worldwide against a production budget of $17 million.
A fifth installment, titled Evil Dead Rise, was released by Warner Bros.
Pictures on April 21, 2023.
The film explores themes of evil spirit, remake,
demon, survival horror, book of the dead.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.